<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>scene on Samba Njie</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tags/scene/</link>
    <description>Recent content in scene on Samba Njie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 11:14:48 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/tags/scene/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Neural Networks for Low Vision Patient Representation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/project-1_lowva/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/post/project-1_lowva/</guid>
      <description>Although almost 3 million adults in the United States are visually impaired, referral rates to visual rehabilitation services are extremely low, despite the ability of these services to improve quality of life. If predictive algorithms could be developed to identify which patients with visual impairment could most benefit from low vision rehabilitation services, referrals could be made in a more automated fashion to facilitate access to these services.
Our project aims to develop predictive algorithms leveraging structured (numeric, coded) and unstructured (free-text notes) clinical information in electronic health records (EHR) data to predict the prognosis of patients with low vision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boston Housing Project</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/project-4_boston_housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/post/project-4_boston_housing/</guid>
      <description>Machine learning project where I used various dimension reduction/feature selection machine learning models such as ridge regression and lasso regression, as well as best subset selection and forward selection, in order to predict Boston housing prices.
housing.csv concerns housing values in suburbs of Boston. The dataset was created by Harrison, D. and Rubinfeld, D.L. and analyzed in &amp;lsquo;Hedonic prices and the demand for clean air&amp;rsquo;, J. Environment Economics and Management, vol.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
