<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Samba Njie</title>
    <link>https://snjie209.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Samba Njie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://snjie209.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Neural Networks for Low Vision Patient Representation</title>
      <link>https://snjie209.github.io/post/project-1_lowva/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://snjie209.github.io/post/project-1_lowva/</guid>
      <description>Although almost 3 million adults in the United States are visually impaired, referral rates to visual rehabilitation services are extremely low, despite the ability of these services to improve quality of life. If predictive algorithms could be developed to identify which patients with visual impairment could most benefit from low vision rehabilitation services, referrals could be made in a more automated fashion to facilitate access to these services.
Our project aims to develop predictive algorithms leveraging structured (numeric, coded) and unstructured (free-text notes) clinical information in electronic health records (EHR) data to predict the prognosis of patients with low vision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stroop Effect Statistical Analysis</title>
      <link>https://snjie209.github.io/post/project-2_stroop_effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://snjie209.github.io/post/project-2_stroop_effect/</guid>
      <description>End-to-end data analysis project testing statistically significant treatment effects for inhibiting automatic word and color associations for within-subjects design. Developed testable hypotheses, measurable results, performed decisions based on goodness-of-fit quantitative tests, and analyzed experimental design and results.
Github: https://github.com/snjie209/StroopEffectProject</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Time Series Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://snjie209.github.io/post/project-3_goog_ts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://snjie209.github.io/post/project-3_goog_ts/</guid>
      <description>This project attempts to understand data from Google Trends and perform time series forecasting using trends data from January 2004 to January 2014.
  Github: https://github.com/snjie209/GoogleTimeSeries</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Database</title>
      <link>https://snjie209.github.io/post/project-6_music_db/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://snjie209.github.io/post/project-6_music_db/</guid>
      <description>Project Requirements: Personal Collection-Database Application Project: Front-End Application via JDBC
Goals Develop a user-friendly Java application that a database built from MySQL. Specifically, the interactive program should behave as a front-end to your database application using Java.
Your program should consist of a simple interface, that is either text-based or GUI-based, in which:
 A list of at least five alternative options is offered to the user. The user selects an alternative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hillary Clinton Email Classification</title>
      <link>https://snjie209.github.io/post/project-5_hillary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://snjie209.github.io/post/project-5_hillary/</guid>
      <description>This repository consists of a Machine Learning class final project collaboratively prepared by myself and three other classmates (Max Eddy, Matthew Weglicki, Julio Soldevilla). The goal of the project was to use machine learning models from the course, both supervised and unsupervised, to classify the top 5 senders of Hillary Clinton&amp;rsquo;s released emails after the enactment o the Freedom of Information Act.
About:
• MasterFile.R: All the code needed to do processing of data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boston Housing Project</title>
      <link>https://snjie209.github.io/post/project-4_boston_housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://snjie209.github.io/post/project-4_boston_housing/</guid>
      <description>Machine learning project where I used various dimension reduction/feature selection machine learning models such as ridge regression and lasso regression, as well as best subset selection and forward selection, in order to predict Boston housing prices.
housing.csv concerns housing values in suburbs of Boston. The dataset was created by Harrison, D. and Rubinfeld, D.L. and analyzed in &amp;lsquo;Hedonic prices and the demand for clean air&amp;rsquo;, J. Environment Economics and Management, vol.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
